Zackary Tyler



Recent physics graduate with one year of experience in aerospace engineering, three years of experience in lab work, and five years of education in complex mathematics. My greatest strengths would be my ability to learn and grasp concepts quickly, prepare alternative solutions, be a team player, make long lasting connections between business partners, and being results driven.



Education

University of California, Davis

Physics B.S. • Political Science Minor

- Quantum Mechanics
- Subatomic Particle Physics
 - Computational Physics
- Electricity & Magnetism •
- Differential Equations
- Circuitry
- **Analytical Mechanics**
- Elementary Particle Physics
- Solid State Physics

(August 2014 – May 2017)

(Sept. 2017 – June 2019)

San Diego State University Aerospace Engineering Major

- Solid Modeling
- **Thermodynamics**
- Statics
- Programming

Applied Mathematics

Experience

DWF Astronomy Project • SDSU, CA

(February 2017)

- Conducted data analysis for luminescence provided by astronomical observatories.
- Reported likely Fast Radio Burst candidates not described under Guide Star Catalog.
- Worked in a global environment coordinating with participants and partners in Chile and Australia.

EOP Tutor • SDSU, CA

(Nov. 2016 - Jan. 2017)

- Mentored and tutored university students in STEM courses from Trig. to Calculus
- Performed key office duties such as scheduling appointments and answering student queries.
- Developed expertise in chemistry and mathematics to improve tutoring abilities.

KPFF Civil Engineering Intern • Roseville, CA

(June - Aug. 2015)

- Assisted in surveying properties' existing structural framing.
- Worked closely with the goals of the architect and owner by attending meetings at key job sites.
- Composed structural calculations to assess a building's center of mass and rigidity.
- Edited and reviewed sketches for managerial approval.
- Shadowed engineers and proactively aided with a variety of tasks.

Rocket Project Member • SDSU, CA

(Aug. 2014 - May 2015)

- Participated in a hands-on experience constructing a liquid fuel rocket.
- Developed experience in plumbing, metal working, and structural composites.
- Successfully performed rocket tests in the Mojave Desert.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- 2013 Air Force Reserve Officer Training Corp Flight Commander, Whitney High School, Rocklin, CA – (Awarded: Tuskegee Airman Ribbon)
- 2013 Air Force Reserve Officer Training Corp Special Events Color Guard Member, Whitney High School, Rocklin, CA

Personal Info

Address 4024 Settlers Ridge Way Roseville CA, 95747

Phone

+ 1 (916) 899-1991

zacktyler2014@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/ zackary-tyler-630054127

Skills

Microsoft Office C++/Pvthon Photoshop/Adobe Software Creo/Solidworks Blender 3D Modeling Linux Systems Briefing & Presentation Matlab Hardware Assembly Laboratory Operations Data Analysis

References

Dan Alwardt: KPFF Manager (916) 206-3615

Vikram Verma: CEO of HSoft (916) 540-6904

Dolores Lopez: Substitute Teacher (530) 305-9006

Misc. Work Experience

July 2019 - Present Choomee Logistics Operations

May 2018 - July 2019 Lyft & Doordash Driver

June 2017 - Sept. 2017 Tilly's Sales Associate

May 2013 - April 2014 Golfland Arcade Tech

March 2013 - June 2014 Tri-City Snack Bar Manager